Guide to the Felix Bloch Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1990-099
  - Photograph of Bloch and J.E. Wallace Sterling, inscribed by Sterling, 1952 (Box 18 oversize)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2002-153
  - Entropy, Energy & specific heat at low temperatures with continuous energy levels – mathematical formulas (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Note re canonical transformation from [illegible], 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Transformation & proof (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Phase space – manuscript (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Thermodynamics – manuscript (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Canonical transformation – manuscript (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hamilton's Equation – manuscript (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Classical mechanics – manuscript (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fundamentals of statistical mechanics – manuscript (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Poisson brackets and canonical transformation – manuscript (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Josephson effect, lecture notes, 1968-70 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Short history of superconductivity, lecture notes, Honolulu, Sept. 6, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Statistical mechanics, lecture notes, Jerusalem, winter 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Statistical mechanics, lecture notes, spring 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Statistical mechanics, lecture notes, spring 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Statistical mechanics, lecture notes, spring 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Statistical mechanics, lecture notes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Statistical mechanics, problem sets, 1934-59 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Statistical mechanics, problem sets, 1962-65 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Statistical mechanics, problem sets, 1969/70 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Statistical mechanics, problem sets, 1975-79 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Statistical mechanics, problem sets (original), 1962-76 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Statistical mechanics, notes, 1949 and n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Statistical mechanics (??), notes (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Statistical mechanics (old edition) – manuscript (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Statistical mechanics, manuscript, pp. 1-34 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Statistical mechanics, manuscript, pp. 35-72 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2010-024
  - Collected papers of Felix Bloch: 3 bound volumes. (Box 1)
    “This collection was undertaken with the encouragement of Professors Marvin Chodorow and Walter Meyerhof. It was assembled through the efforts of three dedicated members of the Physics Department staff: Virginia Bonnici, Bobbe Fowlie, and Bogar Tesszary.” Each volume has a table of contents. Volume 1 covers 1928-1934; Volume 2 covers 1934-1951; Volume 3 covers 1951-1970.